<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<PackageSet>
	<Package>
		<Project>
			<Project>
				<ProjectID>
					<ArchiveID accession="KAP240815" archive="DDBJ"></ArchiveID>
				</ProjectID>
				<ProjectDescr>
					<Title>APOBEC3A, not APOBEC3B, drives deaminase mutagenesis in human gastric epithelium</Title>
					<Description>Cancer genomes frequently carry APOBEC (apolipoprotein B mRNA editing catalytic polypeptide-like)-associated DNA mutations, suggesting APOBEC enzymes as innate mutagens during cancer initiation and/or evolution. However, the pure mutagenic impacts of the specific enzymes among this family that are responsible for APOBEC-associated mutagenesis remain unclear, particularly the comparative mutagenic activities of APOBEC3A and APOBEC3B. Here, we investigated the mutagenic contributions of these enzymes through whole-genome sequencing of human normal gastric organoid lines carrying doxycycline-inducible APOBEC3A or APOBEC3B cassettes. Our findings demonstrated that transcriptional APOBEC3A upregulation led to the acquisition of a massive number of genomic mutations in a few cell cycles. By contrast, APOBEC3B upregulation did not generate a substantial number of mutations in gastric epithelium. APOBEC3B-associated mutagenesis remained insignificant even after a combined inactivation of TP53. Based on the spectrum of acquired mutations after APOBEC3A upregulation, we further analyzed APOBEC3A-associated mutational signatures, encompassing indels mainly composed of 1bp deletions, characteristics of clustered mutations, and selective pressures operative on cells carrying the mutations. Our observations provide a clear foundation for understanding the mutational impact of APOBEC enzymes in human cells.</Description>
					<Grant GrantId="N/A">
						<Title>N/A</Title>
						<Agency abbr="N/A">N/A</Agency>
					</Grant>
					<ProjectReleaseDate>2024-09-04</ProjectReleaseDate>
				</ProjectDescr>
				<ProjectType>
					<ProjectTypeSubmission>
						<Target sample_scope="eOther" material="eOther" capture="eOther">
							<Organism taxID="32644">
								<OrganismName>unidentified</OrganismName>
							</Organism>
						</Target>
						<Method method_type="eOther"></Method>
						<Objectives>
							<Data data_type="eOther"></Data>
						</Objectives>
						<ProjectDataTypeSet>
							<DataType>Other</DataType>
						</ProjectDataTypeSet>
					</ProjectTypeSubmission>
				</ProjectType>
			</Project>
		</Project>
		<Submission>
			<Submission submitted="2024-09-03">
				<Description>
					<Organization type="center" role="owner">
						<Name>Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology</Name>
						<Contact email="kobic_ddbj@kobic.kr">
							<Name>
								<First></First>
								<Last></Last>
							</Name>
						</Contact>
					</Organization>
					<Access>public</Access>
				</Description>
			</Submission>
		</Submission>
	</Package>
</PackageSet>